welcome to meditating with genre vicky
we do this live stream every weekday
morning at 9 30 a.m
with monday's alternating between a new
lesson which was called the dharma day
and the review of the whole ecology of
practices of piou day
the pioneers are going to start
alternating between the review of the
eastern ecology practice
and the western ecology of practice that
comes from
the wisdom of hypatia course you're
joining us for the first time you're
most welcome
uh for previous lessons and sits see the
description in this video
i strongly recommend you go and do
lesson one immediately
then do one or two lessons um a week and
continue to meet with us as you're also
doing that
um so that will get you
integrated fairly quickly into the
course
and into the sega
i would ask if everybody could help me
to reach as many people as possible by
liking this video streamtooth
video screen to increase its visibility
in the youtube algorithm
at the end of every session there are uh
there's q
a please limit your questions to the
ecology of practices
we'll tend to give priority to questions
from the western tradition from monday
wednesday
and friday and to the eastern tradition
from tuesday thursday today's thursday
so that means priority will be given to
questions uh from the eastern tradition
if you're interested in more general
questions uh tomorrow
at 3 30 p.m live stream on youtube will
be my general q
a and you're most welcome to join and
ask
more comprehensive questions there
um just to let everyone know um i'm not
feeling that well today so if i see my
affect seems a little bit off
i'll please don't misinterpret it or
miss
miss b sort of mistake me for conveying
something that i'm not conveying
i'm very happy to be here i always find
this nourishing
i want to do my utmost to help everyone
so
let's go into our set uh we will begin
with chanting
and then we will go into the silence set
we'll come out and we'll have some
time for a q a so please get yourself
into position set your phones and do not
disturb
we will all begin together with the
chanting when i say it again
[Music]
begin
one
[Music]
on
one
[Music]
on
one
[Music]
can you silence it
you
so
so like a lot of your practice trying as
best you can to integrate what you
cultivated in your practice with your
everyday consciousness cognition
character and communicate perhaps by
reciting the five promises
so
take a couple of questions today
a reminder and many of you are doing
this now and it's much appreciated
please share your observations and your
edifications
as well as your questions reminder we'll
be going a little bit longer on monday
wednesdays and fridays
we emphasize the western traditions on
those days
the western traditions on those days in
the eastern traditions
actually it's better to use the plural
on tuesdays and thursdays
as well all right um this is from the
self-improvement journey
uh john what is your view
on brahma charia um
i i'm ignorant of it i don't know what
what that is
um the fact that it has brahma in it
might mean that it comes from pedanta
um i have some familiarity with vedanta
i've studied the upanishads
and some of the work of sankara and some
secondary sources around it
um i've done uh yoga um
that's within the pedantic tradition
so i have some familiarity with vedanta
but the specific
practice you're you're you're talking
about i don't know
i'm sorry i can't really help you that
much perhaps if you
uh rephrase your question and talked
about it more
in terms of questions concerning
practices
related uh to what the practices we're
doing here the ecology practices
and maybe i could answer your question
in a more helpful manner
another question from dimitar welcome
divatar i tried saving a few times so
far
at least initially abnormal to get the
sense that you're like in a dream
um almost like it's surreal yes that is
normal
this is normal because in a dream you
you have your
you you have that participatory sense of
the environment because your mind is
both generating
your your dream ego image and all of the
images around you so there is that sense
of
the dream is co-presencing and then
you're trying to realize
um that there's something deeply
analogous to that in your everyday
experience the way the world
and your consciousness are co-present
synced together
so yes it often has a dream like almost
um mythological uh aspect to it um
i'm doing more research into it right
now but i have at least a primo facial
intuition
that this is similar to some aspects of
you know uh
of indigenous cultures where they're
they're walking the song lines and
they're in the dream time
um and things like that so i think there
is
a phenomenological and functional basis
for what you're
you're describing and is it normal
everything to seem a bit
anthropomorphized like it has a
consciousness
uh or am i doing something else entirely
no that's that is normal
uh that sense of presence especially how
things
seem to be present saying in
a resonant fashion with you uh so that
magical
musicality of the beauty of
intelligibility
is both inside and outside and so
what's typically happening is
things are becoming anthropomorphized so
the tree is becoming anthropomorphized
and the rock is becoming
anthropomorphized
but you're also becoming rockified and
trified
both are happening it's kind of um a
phenomenological
symbolic version of shamanic
shape-shifting in which
you're assuming the identities of things
by affording them a sense of presencing
to you
in a way that's analogous to the way
things presents to you
um in um being alive and so the way to
think about it is a deep continuity
the way your consciousness is present to
you is very strongly present
and then the way living things are
present to you is
also quite salient but not quite as much
as
your unconsciousness and then that is in
continuity with the way all
things are are present to you uh
and so um it's very much the case that
we are using
um sort of this
reciprocal projection and interjection
while we're safering
the important thing is is to experience
that
musically and symbolically and of course
not to take it up as
some kind of well actual
supernatural magic or anything like that
again that is that is to
engage in a fundamental modal confusion
of relating to the mystery with metaphor
and symbol
of the being mode by trying to have
fights saying no no it's literally the
case
and i can have it and manipulate it
in an egocentric fashion so i hope
that's a helpful answer
to your question but keep doing what
you're doing
it sounds like it's bang on
so i want to thank everyone for joining
today
uh amari isn't with us again today so
i'm just gonna
uh he did some work earlier to help us
out this morning
that's why we're slightly late uh but
jason has been doing everything behind
the scenes
so again thank you to my beloved son
please subscribe to the channel to be
notified of the next video
you'll find links to the uh lecture
series awakening from the meaning crisis
the
logo series voices with raviki there's a
new series on consciousness untangling
the world
not it's going to be released soon and
then a little bit down the road
um the elusive self is going to be
released
and of course as soon as we can get
stably
beyond all the coveted limitations we're
going to be getting the filming of after
socrates so there's a lot
of richness there um please
uh follow me on twitter to be uploaded
about the streams
and get any quick notifications about
sudden changes that might be happening
like for example to the
sip today or for the live streaming on
friday
please join the discord server to chat
with others the link is in the
description
they're doing an extra sitting
there they do the movement practices
like
they're doing group luxio uh mark and
manuel were describing some of the
ways they've extended the luxio to group
practice i think this is
wonderful i encourage us to keep going
um i'm
i've already spoken to brett and mark
we're going to work out the details
but the discord servers were going to
hone the group practices
that are so central to the wisdom of
hypatia so please get involved with that
um
where and when and to the degree that
you can
i understand we're in another trend
we're in a transition within that
transition
so covet is this sort of world
encompassing transition liminal period
and then within it we're sort of
transitioning back to
normality but it's not what it used to
be and it's chaotic and i get that
um and so let's all be very open
take deep breaths savor the pure joy of
being and try and sail
you know through those winds of
uncertainty
in a way that has um
a sense of joyous coupling to the
tumultuous flow
of events
so a reminder that tomorrow
is the live q a at 3 p.m
eastern time i hope to see all of you
there
remember that continuity of practice is
more important than quantity of practice
don't hold yourself to a standard
of harsh perfectionism by virtuous
friendship
because there's no enemy worse than your
own mind and body but there's no
friend no ally no true companion on the
path better than your own mind on body
please be lapsed onto yourselves and to
each other
i'll see you tomorrow take good care
everyone
bye-bye
you